Neha Patil

Data scientist

A Professional Data Scientist with more than 1.7 years of experience in Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Financial Markets and Data Modelling. Involved in enforcing Cash Flow Forecasting Strategies, developing trading strategies, creating data pipelines and visualizations for BFSI Domains . Actively seeking a job in Machine learning / Data scientist.

nehapatil364@gmail.com

+91-902-829-3272

Linkedin, Website

WORK EXPERIENCE:

Intellect Design Arena (Pune, MH)

July 2019 - Present

Data scientist

- Successfully designed & implemented a cash flow forecasting model that predicts the
 income and outcome of customer based on that recommend customer need to take loan or
 invest the balance money In bank.
- Successfully designed & implemented Alexa skill/ chatbot development for Corporate bank.
- Build NLP Pipeline Using Spacy, NLTK, Data Preprocessing using Pyspark.
- Create a Dashboard using Dash and Plotly To show Transaction analysis.
- Create End-to-end Machine learning Model (Django) and Deploy On a cloud.
- Hands on experience on Machine Learning algorithms like LSTM, sequences, Time series analysis, ARIMA, SARIMA, Prediction, etc..
- Processing, cleansing, and verifying, real time data, the integrity of data used for analysis.

BridgeLabz Solutions LLP (Mumbai, MH)

Feb 2019 -- July 2019

Machine Learning Engineer / Data scientist (Fellowship)

- House price prediction using the linear regression model, decision tree, random forest, Spam mail detection using logistic regression, and all other classifier models Clusters and analysis using KNN, Hierarchical clustering, NLP.
- Worked on Deep learning models and have an understanding of Forward propagation, Backward propagation, RNN, CNN,etcAge detection, Image classification, Data visualization Using Different visualization Library.
- Deployed Machine learning model using flask on AWS.

TCI Tech Foundation (Banglore, KA)

May 2018 -- June 2018

Web Developer Intern

- Crafted front end of the system using HTML, CSS and Javascript.
- Autofilled user details using user's resume.
- Involved in testing of given requirements specifications.

EDUCATION

SKILL

- Languages: Python, SQL, HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript, Nodejs.
- **DB and Libraries**: MySQL, postgresql, Pandas, Numpy, Scikit-learn, Matplotlib, plotly, seaborn, spaCy, OpenCy, Tensorflow, Keras, Pyspark, RNN, LSTM.
- Big Data/Data Engineering: Apache Spark, Streaming API, Kafka .
- **DevOps/Tools**: Git, Bitbucket, AWS, Google cloud, Heroku, Power BI, Tableau, Kibana, Elasticsearch.
- Frameworks : Django, Flask, Dash.
- **Machine Learning**: Computer vision, Deep learning, Convolution Neural Network, Time series analysis, NLP.
- **Other**: REST API, GraphqlApi, Web scraping, Beautiful Soup, AWS lambda, Alexa skill kit, RASA NLU, ChabotDevelopment, Amazon Developer consol, NLTK.

CERTIFICATIONS:

- IBM Deep learning Using TensorFlow.
- Deep Learning specialization
- Applied Data Science with Python Specialization
- Python for Everybody Specialization
- Publication Certificate and National Level participation certificate.